Finding Aid for Suomi College Finnish-American collection, 1880-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Suomi College Finnish-American collection 1880-1972
Suomi College.
89318 Bd microcopy
The Finnish Collection consists of 100 reels of microfilm concerning Finnish-American Churches, Labor Societies, Temperance Organizations, and other materials from the United States and Canada. The collection is the result of a joint project between the Bentley Library, Suomi College (now Finlandia University), and the University of Turku, Finland, coordinated in 1974-75.
100 microfilms
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The microfilm collection was received by arrangement with the college in 1975.
No further additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Finnish Collection consists of 100 reels of microfilm concerning Finnish-American Churches, Labor Societies, Temperance Organizations, and other materials from the United States and Canada. The contents were filmed at the Suomi College (now Finlandia University) Historical Archive and are the result of a joint project between the Bentley Library, Suomi College (now Finlandia University), and the University of Turku, Finland, coordinated in 1974-75. Much of the fieldwork and cataloging of the Finnish Collection at the Bentley Historical Library, including the obtaining of materials, was performed by Keijo Virtanen, doctoral candidate at the University of Turku who held a Research Assistantship at the Michigan Historical Collections in 1974-1975.
The Suomi College Finnish-American Collection is comprised of 100 reels of microfilm containing records from 151 separate organizations (68 of which are located in Michigan). These organizations are comprised of the following kinds of records:
Church materials: 62 record groups (32 from Michigan)
Labor societies: 9 record groups (0 from Michigan)
Temperance materials: 61 record groups (26 from Michigan
Other organizations, including educational, relief, musical, athletic, national, historical societies, publishing companies, and some personal: 19 record groups (10 from Michigan)
Because the materials have been filmed in a random order, an index at the end of the container listing has been prepared to guide the researcher to specific kinds of records: church, temperance, etc.
Subjects:
Amasa (Mich.)--Church history.; Baraga (Mich.); Calumet (Mich.); Chassell (Mich.); Coburntown (Mich.); Covington (Mich.)--Church history.; Crystal Falls (Mich.)--Church history.; Elo (Mich.)--Church history.; Grand Marais (Mich.)--Church history.; Gwinn (Mich.)--Church history.; Hancock (Mich.)--Church history.; Iron County (Mich.); Iron Mountain (Mich.); Ironwood (Mich.)--Church history.; L'Anse (Mich.)--Church history.; Laird (Mich.)--Church history.; Marquette County (Mich.); Metropolitan (Mich.)--Church history.; Munising (Mich.)--Church history.; National Mine (Mich.)--Church history.; Negaunee (Mich.); Newberry (Mich.)--Church history.; Nisula (Mich.)--Church history.; Norway (Mich.)--Church history.; Oskar (Mich.); Palmer (Mich.)--Church history.; Pelkie (Mich.)--Church history.; Pequaming (Mich.)--Church history.; Princeton (Mich.)--Church history.; Ramsay (Mich.)--Church history.; Redridge (Mich.); Rockland (Mich.); Rudyard (Mich.); Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.)--Church history.; Shafer (Mich.); Stambaugh (Mich.)--Church history.; Suomi (Mich.)--Church history.; Tamarack (Mich.); Toivola (Mich.); Trout Creek (Mich.); Wakefield (Mich.)--Church history.; Winona (Mich.); United States--Emigration and immigration.; Finnish Americans--Michigan.; Finnish Americans.; Labor movement--United States.; Labor unions--United States.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan.; Temperance--United States.; Finland--Emigration and immigration.; Immigrants--United States.
- Finnish-American Collection: Church Records, Labor Societies, Temperance Organizations, and others
  - Temperance Society Suomen Ruusu [The Rose of Finland], Cleveland, Ohio
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - January 7, 1907-December 18, 1910 (Reel 1)
      - October 10, 1920-May 16, 1926 (Reel 1)
      - December 13, 1936-December 27, 1936 (Reel 1)
      - July 22, 1926-November 29, 1936 (Reel 1)
      - January 10, 1937-July 13, 1947 (Reel 1)
      - February 5, 1948-February 1, 1949 (Reel 2)
    - Minute book (entertainment committee)
      - March 2, 1915-May 16, 1916 (Reel 2)
  - Temperance Society Toivon Sankari [The Hero of the Hope], Youngstown, Ohio
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - May 5, 1907-January 26, 1908 (Reel 2)
      - April 1, 1905-October 29, 1905 (Reel 2)
      - June 23, 1907-December 3, 1911 (Reel 2)
      - February 9, 1908-April 5, 1909 (Reel 2)
      - April 11, 1909-January 2, 1910 (Reel 2)
    - A play called Parittomat [The Odd] (Reel 2)
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - January 2, 1910-February 6, 1910 (Reel 2)
      - January 9, 1910-November 13, 1910 (Reel 2)
      - August 19, 1911-April 7, 1912 (Reel 2)
      - April 14, 1912-April 20, 1913 (Reel 2)
      - April 27, 1913-December 20, 1914 (Reel 3)
      - January 10, 1915-April 1, 1917 (Reel 3)
      - April 8, 1917-July 24, 1920 (Reel 3)
  - The Accident, Illness and Burial Relief Society of Monessen, Pennsylvania
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - April 20, 1918-January 6, 1935 (Reel 3)
      - February 3, 1929-July 12, 1936 Baltimore chapter (Reel 3)
      - January 13, 1929-December 15, 1953 Warren, Ohio chapter (Reel 3)
      - November 15, 1931-January 14, 1934 East Chicago, Indiana chapter (Reel 3)
      - August 20, 1944-March 1-5, 1953 Baltimore chapter) (Reel 3)
  - Temperance Society Uuudenvuoden Lahja [The Gift of the New Year], Lowellville, Ohio
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - August 26, 1906-December 9, 1906 (Reel 3)
  - Swedish-Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Norway, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 4)
    - Baptisms (Reel 4)
    - Confirmations (Reel 4)
    - Marriages (Reel 4)
    - Reception of members (Reel 4)
    - Dismissal of members (Reel 4)
    - Funerals (Reel 4)
    - Minute book (official meetings, in Swedish)
      - December 30, 1880-December 13, 1908 (Reel 4)
    - List of trustees 1891-1908 (Reel 4)
    - Program for the 25th Anniversary 1905 (Reel 4)
    - Minute books (in Swedish)
      - September 30, 1891-August 20, 1895 (official meetings) (Reel 4)
      - August 27, 1895-December 6, 1898 (young people's committee) (Reel 4)
      - October 17, 1911-1917 (Sunday school) (Reel 4)
      - September 10, 1919-1922 (women's committee) (Reel 4)
      - January 8, 1913-November 30, 1916 (daughters' committee) (Reel 4)
      - January 11, 1902-November 3, 1912 (church council) (Reel 4)
      - January 1, 1909-April 17, 1926 (official meetings) (Reel 4)
      - October 30, 1909-February 19, 1921 (men's committee) (Reel 4)
      - March 4, 1911-December 28, 1928 (trustee board,) (Reel 4)
  - Swedish-Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Metropolitan, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 5)
    - Baptisms (Reel 5)
    - Confirmations (Reel 5)
    - Marriages (Reel 5)
    - Reception of members (Reel 5)
    - Dismissal of members (Reel 5)
    - Funerals (Reel 5)
    - Constitution of the church (Reel 5)
    - Minute Books (in Swedish)
      - August 13, 1908-January 11, 1913 (various meetings, in Swedish) (Reel 5)
      - January 25, 1913-1917 (various meetings, in Swedish) (Reel 5)
      - January 6, 1915-1916 (women's committee, in Swedish) (Reel 5)
    - Willing Workers (in Swedish)
      - Constitution of the Willing Workers and a minute book August 4, 1906-August 21, 1908 (Reel 5)
      - Minute book September 8, 1908-December 21, 1912 (Reel 5)
  - The Archives of Rev. Arvi Henri Saarisuu (Crystal Falls, Michigan)
    - Poetry: Amerikan pilgriimit [The Pilgrims of America] (Reel 5)
    - Manuscript of the thesis for the degree of Master of Sacred Theology (Reel 5)
    - Problems of Transition to American Church Life for the Finnish Christian (Reel 5)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Crystal Falls, Michigan
    - Church book No. 1: clippings, members, Baptisms, Marriages (Reel 5)
    - Church book No. 2: members (Reel 6)
    - Church book No. 2a: members (Reel 6)
    - Minute book
      - December 3, 1948-December 2, 1960 (deacons) (Reel 6)
    - Membership book (Reel 6)
    - Membership book (Reel 6)
    - Minute book (official meetings, in Swedish)
      - July 10, 1894-1916 (Reel 6)
    - Cash book
      - 1894-1910 (Reel 6)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Stambaugh, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 7)
    - Minute Books (official meetings)
      - May 28, 1911-February 8, 1931 (Reel 7)
      - January 22, 1933-April 26, 1953 (Reel 7)
      - 1910-1919 (summer school) (Reel 7)
      - February 10, 1923-February 5, 1937 (Reel 7)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Amasa, Michigan
    - Membership book No. 1 (Reel 7)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 7)
  - Swedish-Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Amasa, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 7)
    - Minute book (official meetings, in Swedish)
      - February 10, 1901-January 6, 1957 (Reel 7)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Pequaming, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 7)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Covington, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 7)
    - Baptisms (Reel 7)
    - Confirmations (Reel 7)
    - Marriages (Reel 7)
    - Funerals (Reel 7)
    - Minute books
      - May 7, 1900-November 7, 1926 (official meetings) (Reel 7)
      - 1927-November 16, 1939 (official meetings) (Reel 7)
      - January 6, 1913-October 22, 1929 (sewing circle) (Reel 7)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of L'Anse, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 8)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Uusi Suomi [New Finland], Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 8)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of National Mine [Winthrop], Michigan
    - Membership book No. 1 (Reel 8)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 8)
    - Minute book (official meeting)
      - January 28, 1912-February 4, 1940 (Reel 8)
    - Cash book of the library 1903-1905 (Reel 8)
    - Account book of the church 1905-1939 (Reel 8)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Palmer, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 8)
    - Minute books
      - October 30, 1890-October 7, 1906 (official meetings) (Reel 8)
      - January 6, 1907-April 8, 1923 (official meetings) (Reel 8)
      - January 9, 1910-April 30, 1954 (church council) (Reel 8)
    - Cash book 1889-1930 (Reel 8)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Princeton, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 9)
    - Cash book 1925-1945 (Reel 9)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Gwinn, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 9)
    - Baptisms (Reel 9)
    - Confirmations (Reel 9)
    - Marriages (Reel 9)
    - Funerals (Reel 9)
    - Minute book (Sunday school teachers)
      - January 19, 1942-January 15, 1959 (Reel 9)
  - Swedish-Finnish Congregation of Grand Marais, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 9)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Munising, Michigan
    - Minute books
      - February 27, 1947-May 17, 1956 (Lutheran Guild) (Reel 9)
      - February 18, 1943-January 31, 1954 (official meetings) (Reel 9)
      - January 20, 1955-January 9, 1965 (official meetings) (Reel 10)
    - A History of the Trout Creek Evangelical Lutheran Church (English, manuscript) (Reel 10)
  - Swedish-Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Munising, Michigan
    - Membership book (started in 1905) (Reel 10)
    - Baptisms 1906-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Confirmations 1907-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Marriages 1906-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Reception of members 1924-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Dismissal of members 1925-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Funerals 1915-1972 (Reel 10)
    - Minute books
      - January 3, 1907-1939 (official meetings) (Reel 10)
      - January 8, 1920-July 17, 1924 (women's committee) (Reel 10)
  - Temperance Society Onnen Aarre [The Treasure of Happiness], Newberry, Michigan
    - Cash book 1906 (Reel 10)
  - Swedish-Finnish Congregation of Newberry, Michigan
    - Baptisms 1903-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Confirmations 1904-1963 (Reel 10)
    - Marriages 1903-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Reception of members 1959-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Dismissal of members 1905-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Funerals 1909-1966 (Reel 10)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Newberry, Michigan
    - Baptisms 1908-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Confirmations 1908-1964 (Reel 10)
    - Marriages 1911-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Reception of members 1955-1958 (Reel 10)
    - Funerals 1910-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Membership book No. I (Reel 10)
    - Membership book No. II (Reel 10)
    - Membership book No. II (cont) (Reel 11)
    - Minute books
      - September 24, 1889-October 10, 1920 (official meetings) (Reel 11)
      - January 9, 1921-October 19, 1953 (official meetings) (Reel 11)
      - January 13, 1938-November 21, 1951 (church council) (Reel 11)
      - November 20, 1913-February 4, 1941 (YWCA) (Reel 11)
      - September 12, 1935-May 12, 1941 (sewing circle) (Reel 11)
      - June 1, 1942-December 19, 1949 (sewing circle) (Reel 11)
    - Diary 1911-1914 (church school) (Reel 11)
  - Swedish-Finnish Congregation of Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 12)
    - Baptisms 1927-1964 (Reel 12)
    - Confirmations 1927-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Marriages 1934-1962 (Reel 12)
    - Reception of members 1927-1962 (Reel 12)
    - Dismissal of members 1933-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Funerals 1929-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Membership book No. I (Reel 12)
    - Membership book No. II (started in 1918) (Reel 12)
    - Membership book No. III (Reel 12)
    - Baptisms 1921-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Confirmations 1921-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Marriages 1922-1962 (Reel 12)
    - Burials 1923-1963 (Reel 12)
    - Diary 1954-1960 (church school) (Reel 12)
  - Temperance Society Hyvä Toivo [Good Hope], Calumet, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - January 31, 1886-April 28, 1889 (Reel 12)
    - List of members
      - 1885-1888 (Reel 12)
    - Rules (Reel 12)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Laird, Michigan
    - Baptisms 1927-1947 (Reel 12)
    - Baptisms 1947-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Confirmations 1927-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Marriages 1928-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Burials 1927-1961 (Reel 13)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Elo, Michigan
    - Membership book (started in 1933) (Reel 13)
    - 40th Anniversary Celebration July 19, 1953 (English, printed) (Reel 13)
    - Baptisms 1927-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Confirmations 1927-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Marriages 1929-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Burials 1928-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - December 22, 1935-April 15, 1945 (Reel 13)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Nisula, Michigan
    - Membership book No. I (Reel 13)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 13)
    - Nisulan Evangelical Lutheran, Seurakunnan historia [The History of the Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Nisula]. Written for the 60th Anniversary Celebration on September 11-12, 1954. Written by Mr. Leino Jacobsson. Printed. (Reel 13)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Pelkie (Kyrö), Michigan
    - History of the congregation, written for the 50th Anniversary Celebration on July 30-31, 1955 (manuscript) (Reel 13)
    - Membership book (started in 1933) (Reel 13)
    - Officers of the congregation 1915-1916 (Reel 13)
    - Members 1905-1917 (Reel 13)
    - Baptisms 1904-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Confirmations 1918-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Marriages 1905-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Burials 1928-1960 (Reel 13)
    - Membership book No. 1 (started in 1905) (Reel 13)
    - Minute book
      - January 1, 1905-May 26, 1929 (official meetings) (Reel 13)
      - June 30, 1929-October 2, 1935 (official meetings) (Reel 14)
      - June 22, 1930-October 25, 1944 (congregation circle) (Reel 14)
  - Finnish National Lutheran Congregation of Ironwood, Mich.
    - Membership book No. 1 (Reel 14)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 14)
    - Membership book No. 2 (cont) (Reel 15)
    - Marriages 1897-1951 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1897-1902 (Reel 15)
    - Funerals 1942-1951 (Reel 15)
  - Finnish National Lutheran Congregation of Ironwood, Mich.
    - Funerals 1897-1898 (Reel 15)
    - Confirmations 1897-1898 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1902-1905 (Reel 15)
    - Marriages 1904-1908 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1907-1908 (Reel 15)
    - Confirmations 1904-1907 (Reel 15)
    - Marriages 1908-1909 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1905-1907 (Reel 15)
    - Funerals 1902-1909 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1909-1915 (Reel 15)
    - Baptisms 1916-1918 (Reel 16)
    - Confirmations 1948 (Reel 16)
    - Confirmations 1910-1923 (Reel 16)
    - Marriages 1910-1934 (Reel 16)
    - Confirmations 1924-1947 (Reel 16)
    - Baptisms 1928-1951 (Reel 16)
    - Marriages 1934-1948 (Reel 16)
    - Confirmations 1949-1951 (Reel 16)
    - Funerals 1909-1942 (Reel 16)
    - Baptisms 1933-1934 (Reel 16)
    - Marriages 1932-1936 (Reel 16)
    - Marriages 1899-1903 (Reel 16)
    - Baptisms 1899-1902 (Reel 16)
    - Confirmations 1899-1908 (Reel 16)
    - Funerals 1899-1901 (Reel 16)
    - Minute Books
      - 1935-1941 (official meetings) (Reel 16)
      - February 29, 1912-April 8, 1920 (young people's committee) (Reel 16)
      - January 14, 1915-December 18, 1919 (sewing circle) (Reel 16)
      - January 15, 1920-1925 (sewing circle) (Reel 16)
      - May 23, 1935-April 6, 1939 (sewing circle) (Reel 16)
      - April 20, 1939-November 23, 1939 (sewing circle) (Reel 17)
      - December 7, 1939-February 20, 1941 (sewing circle) (Reel 17)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Wakefield, Michigan
    - Membership book No. 1 (Reel 17)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 17)
    - Membership book No. 3 (Reel 17)
    - Baptisms 1904-1921 (Reel 17)
    - Confirmations 1917-1922 (Reel 17)
    - Marriages 1905-1922 (Reel 17)
    - Funerals 1904-1923 (Reel 17)
    - Baptisms 1921-1956 (Reel 17)
    - Confirmations 1923-1958 (Reel 17)
    - Marriages 1924-1957 (Reel 17)
    - Burials 1924-1940 (Reel 17)
    - Minute books
      - March 11, 1914-June 22, 1921 (Christian Young People's Organization) (Reel 17)
      - January 22, 1922-November 7, 1929 (Christian Young People's organization) (Reel 18)
      - January 25, 1917-December 11, 1924 (Ladies Aid) (Reel 18)
    - Cash book 1908-1922 (Sunday School) (Reel 18)
    - Minute books (Sunday School)
      - October 19, 1924-September 6, 1925 (Reel 18)
      - January 16, 1916-May 4, 1924 (Reel 18)
      - September 10, 1909-December 6, 1915 (Reel 18)
    - Rules (Reel 18)
    - Annual reports of the church 1942-1957 (Reel 18)
    - Minute book
      - February 25, 1944-August 29, 1952 (deacons) (Reel 18)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Ramsay, Michigan
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - January 14, 1925-January 6, 1929 (Reel 18)
    - Diary of the minister 1929-1939 (Reel 18)
    - Cash book 1927-1928 (Reel 18)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Iron Belt, Wisconsin
    - Membership book 1919 (Reel 18)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Montreal, Wisconsin
    - Membership book (started in 1920) (Reel 18)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Marengo, Wisconsin
    - Membership book (started in 1918) (Reel 18)
    - Baptisms 1921-1944 (Reel 18)
    - Confirmations 1923-1944 (Reel 18)
    - Funerals 1921-1942 (Reel 18)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Ironwood, Michigan
    - Membership book (Reel 18)
    - Membership book (cont) (Reel 19)
    - Confirmations 1914-1928 (Reel 19)
    - Marriages 1913-1928 (Reel 19)
    - Marriages 1928-1940 (Reel 19)
    - Funerals 1912-1923 (Reel 19)
    - Funerals 1923-1939 (Reel 19)
    - Baptisms 1913-1928 (Reel 19)
    - Ministerial acts of the missionary of the congregation 1891-1903 Baptisms, Confirmations, Marriages, Funerals) (Reel 19)
  - Temperance Society Hyvä Tahto [Good Will], Ashtabula Harbor, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings) (Reel 20)
      - September 25, 1887-May 27, 1888 (Reel 20)
  - Temperance Society Suomen Ruusu [The Rose of Finland], Ashtabula, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - January 5, 1950-1954 (Reel 20)
  - Temperance Society Sovinto [Harmony], Ashtabula, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - January 13, 1923-December 21, 1933 (Reel 20)
      - January 4, 1934-May 11, 1939 11 (Reel 20)
  - Temperance Society Kunto [Condition], Ashtabula, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - July 9, 1893-June 3, 1894 (Reel 20)
      - June 11, 1894-December 15, 1895 (Reel 20)
      - December 18, 1898-September 17, 1899 (Reel 20)
      - December 10, 1899-February 16, 1902 (Reel 21)
  - Temperance Society Hedelmä [Fruit], Warren, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - November 20, 1898-April 24, 1904 (Reel 21)
      - February 14, 1909-August 18, 1912 (Reel 21)
      - March 13, 1913-January 24, 1915 (Reel 21)
    - Minute book (speakers' committee)
      - January 22, 1914-April 16, 1914 (Reel 21)
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - May 23, 1915-December 30, 1917 (Reel 22)
      - June 2, 1935-March 31, 1946 (Reel 22)
      - April 28, 1946 (Reel 22)
  - Temperance Society Toivon Alku [Beginning of the Hope], Girard, Ohio
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - September 25, 1910-June 25, 1911 (Reel 22)
      - March 5, 1922-October 29, 1922 (Reel 22)
      - November 5, 1922-June 5, 1927 (Reel 22)
  - Temperance Society Laakson Ruusu [The Rose of the Valley], Ansonville, Pennsylvania
    - Cash book (Reel 22)
  - Musical Society Sibelius Club (Monessen, Pennsylvania)
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - July 18, 1915-January 24, 1937 (Reel 22)
  - Athletic Club Oma Voima [Self Power], Monessen, Pa.
    - Letters (Reel 22)
    - Ihmiselämää tiettömien taivalten takana. Vetoomus Suomen avustusjärestöille [Human Life Beyond Trackless Distances. An Appeal to the Aid Organizations of Finland]. Printed. (Reel 22)
    - Rules (Reel 22)
    - Minute book (official meetings)
      - November 25, 1916-February 11, 1950 (Reel 22)
  - The Archive of the Finnish-American Historical Society of Michigan (Detroit, Michigan)
    - Delawaren suomalaisten historiaa [The History of the Delaware Finns]. Review by Heikki Waris of John H. Wuorinen's book (Reel 23)
    - The functions of the Finnish American Historical Society (typewritten in English) (Reel 23)
    - Correspondence 1945 (Reel 23)
    - Constitution pf the Finnish American Historical Society of Michigan (in English) (Reel 23)
    - Minute book
      - October 14, 1945- (Reel 23)
    - Clippings (Reel 23)
    - Programs (Reel 23)
    - This is Kaleva (A Brief History of a Finnish Town). Typewritten in English (Reel 23)
    - August Nisula. Pioneer. 1849-1938. Essay by Mrs. M. Keranen. In English (Reel 23)
    - Pioneering in Northern Michigan. Essay by Anna Into. In English (Reel 23)
    - Yläniemekkeen maalaiskyliä, suurmetsät ja suomalaiset [The Villages, the Great Forests and the Finns of Upper Peninsula]: Essay by H.M. Makela (Reel 23)
    - Constitution of the Finlandia Women's Organization (Reel 23)
    - Programs (Reel 23)
    - Photographs (Reel 23)
    - "The Finn-So News' 1938-1940 (Reel 23)
    - Programs (Reel 23)
    - Finnish Album to Commemorate Detroit's 250th Birthday. Printed, in English (Reel 23)
    - Map of Kaleva, Michigan (Reel 23)
  - The Archive of the Historical Museum in Kaleva, Michigan
    - Photographs (Reel 23)
    - Photographs (Reel 24)
    - Minute book (Youth's Society)
      - April 25, 1909-January 21, 1912 (Reel 24)
    - Register of advices received of Domestic Money Orders (Reel 24)
    - Photographs (Reel 24)
    - Minute book (Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Kaleva)
      - January 9, 1949-January 25, 1957 (Reel 24)
    - Biography of Jacob Lemponen (Kaleva, Mich.) (Reel 24)
    - Why the Finnish Names in Kaleva. By Andrew I. Brask. Typewritten, in English (Reel 24)
    - Kalevatar [The Lady Kaleva] (a history) (Reel 24)
    - Articles, rules (Youth or Nouriso Society) (Reel 24)